Guide to the Leland Stanford Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Correspondence, Series 2
  - Incoming
    - L, 1879-1890 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Loch: 9/19/1889 [?] appreciation for visit to Stock farm
    - M, 1874-1893 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - McLaughlin: 4/3/1874 wants payment on account
      - McNally: January 1893 received gift
      - Maynard: 4/19/1890 giving political support
      - Marysville citizens: 9/21/1889 invitation
      - Morehouse: 4/12/1890 giving political support
      - Morton: n.d. enclosing note by request of Duchesse d/Auxy [not attached]
    - N - P, 1868-1889 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Nash: 10/25/1889 (tel) reached San Diego, governor doing fine; 10/27/1889 (tel) governor well but tired
      - Newman: 3/20/1885 Gen. Logan not well, hope you can visit; December 1886 (2 tel) on Gen. Logan's death
      - Parry: 6/8/1887 discovery of a new manzanita named in honor of Leland Stanford Jr. [see OS box for sample]
      - Penfield: 10/19/1868 (tel) prices of teams and men going up (Utah grading work)
      - Pope: 12/26/1884 enclosing letter from Gen. Stoneman [not included]
    - Reid, Whitelaw, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - 1889 Feb. 23: (tel) received your congratulations
    - Sargent, A. A., 1884- 1885 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - 1884 Nov. 11: wants Stanford's aid in senatorial contest
      - 1885 Jan. 11: on the attitude of Chute and the Chronicle in the contest
      - 1885 Jan. 13: wants Haymond and Gage suppressed
    - Schofield, Gen. J. M., 1876- 1891 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - 1876 Oct. 8: invites them to visit West Point
      - 1891 Jan. 12: dinner invitation to meet the President
      - May ?: regrets but cannot accept invitation from the Stanfords
    - Sherman, William T., 1889-1890 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - 1889 February: 2 letters to W. W. Morrow re J. D. Stevenson
      - 1890 May: regrets but cannot accept Stanfords' invitation
    - Stillman/Osgood, 1881- 1883 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Letters between J.D.B. Stillman and publisher James R. Osgood & Company concerning Stillman's book Horse In Motion and Muybridge's claims on the copyright (19 letters)
    - S, 1863-1890 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Sawyer: 4/12/1890 support for Senate campaign
      - Scanlon: 4/11/1890 public opinion is on Stanford's side in spite of newspaper stories
      - Sheridan: 6/7/1886 not sure he can attend GAR meeting in California
      - Sherman: 5/8/1863 going east by overland route, requests letters of introduction
      - Smith, A.: 4/3/1864 mining and railroads in northern California (Ione City)
      - Smith, F.: 9/22/1889 extends invitation to visit citizens of Redding
      - Stanton, E.C.: n.d. [1871] requesting RR passes for self and Miss Anthony
      - Stanton, M. O.: 12/28/1888 sending "physiognomical delineation" of LS Jr. [not attached]
      - Swit: 2/26/1886 on education in New Zealand
    - T - V, 1885-1893 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Talmadge: 4/3/1890 on Stanford's speech on education
      - Towne: n.d. note re railroad tracks and land
      - Treat: 1886-88 1bill, 2 letters on photos Treat took of campus lands; 3/9/1893 (tel) birthday greetings
      - Tripp: 4/19/1890 letter of support
      - Vliet: 4/10/1189 requesting assistance for employment with S. P.
    - W, 1884-1890 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Wallace: 1/16/1884 advises Stanford to keep audience with the Sultan
      - Warwick: [1884 ?] condolences on death of Leland Jr. (missing first page)
      - Wilcox: 4/15/1890 to Col. Haymond in support of Stanford
    - Y, 1876-1889 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Yorke: 9/19/1889 thanking Stanford for visit at Stock Farm
      - Yost: 6/3/1876 (tel) to H. Cummings with payment instructions from Stanford
    - Illegible and fragments, 1880- 1892 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - 3 by same person, 1880-1889, re Stanfords visiting the House of Commons in London and personal matters
      - 1 fragment, on Capitol Police letterhead, 1892, re gavel made from magnolia tree at Mt.Vernon and presented to Stanford U.
      - 1 from "S", San Francisco, 6/1/1890 on state politics, mentions Crocker, Huntington, Haymond, Thomas Bell
    - Telegrams of sympathy, A - L, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Telegrams of sympathy, M - Z, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Business and legal papers, Series 3
  - Alameda County property deeds, 1871-1884 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Alfred A. Cohen to Leland Stanford, deed, October 2, 1871
    - Rose Anna Kell et. al. to Leland Stanford, deed, January 21, 1884
  - Bills and receipts, miscellaneous, 1881-1893 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - furniture bill, New York, 1883
    - various livery and veterinary bills in Washington, DC, 1893
    - jewelry bills, Paris, 1881
  - California Street Cable Railroad Company, 1883-1889 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Agreement with Henry Root, Sept. 1883-July 1, 1884
    - Report of Treasurer, Alfred Borel & Co., July 1889
    - Report of Vice President Antoine Borel, July 1889
    - Bid for switches, Wm. H. Birch & Co., December 1889
    - Copy of letter to L. B. Benchley from Albert Stetson, July 11, 1889
    - Copy of letter to L. B. Benchley from Albert Stetson, July 3, 1889
    - Specifications for five cable cars, J. Hammond & Co.
    - Assignment, August 1, 1884
    - Assignment franchise, Leland Stanford to CSRRC
  - Central Pacific Railroad Company
    - Central Pacific Railroad Company: clippings, 1873- 1889 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Central Pacific Railroad Company: clippings, CPRR v. Cohen, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Central Pacific Railroad Company: deeds, 1865- 1885 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - 1865, Oct. 28: Winchester to Karchner
      - 1867, July 29: CPRR to Barker
      - 1870, Sept. 20: Certificate of Register of Land Office - Marquis C. Winchester
      - 1871, May 29: CPRR to Bader
      - 1871, July 19: CPRR to Wilcoxson
      - 1871, Nov. 13: Wilcoxson to Barker
      - 1871, Nov. 22: Barker to Karchner
      - 1873, March 12: Winchester to Gates
      - 1873, July 8: Gates to Karchner
      - 1877, Feb. 20: CPRR to Ordway and McMillan
      - 1882, July 25: Certificate of Register of Land Office - Karchner (John Smith)
      - 1883, Oct. 24: CPRR to Karchner
      - 1884, April 24: Smith, Ragsdale, Karchner to Karchner
      - 1884, Dec. 20: Certificate of Register of Land Office - Karchner
      - 1885, Oct. 17: CPRR to Karchner
    - Central Pacific Railroad Company: documents, 1866- 1888 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - 1866: Report to Andrew Johnson signed by L. Stanford, Sam S. Montaune, Charles Crocker (photostat)
      - 1868, March 20: Agreement on lands for RR terminus, S.P., C.P., Stanford, Lloyd Tevis, H.N. Carpentier, W. B. Carr and George Hearst
      - 1868, May 31: list of securities, signed by L. Stanford
      - 1868, Dec. 5: L. Stanford note re stock mailed to J. Stanford
      - 1869, Feb. 27: memorandum of securities deposited in name of J. L. Stanford, signed by L. Stanford
      - 1876, June 20: L. Stanford deposition
      - 1878, Sept. 10: A.P. Stanford to L. Stanford, release
      - 1888, Jan. 7: Report in letter form to Rufus Blodgett from Richard (?), inscribed to Stanford
    - Central Pacific Railroad Company: Gold Spike receipt, 1869 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Central Pacific Railroad Company: "History and Defense of the Railroad," signed by Leland Stanford, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Central Pacific Railroad Company: slip case for "History and Defense of the Railroad" (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Central Pacific Railroad Company: printed documents, 1869- 1890 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Brannan and Ives vs. CPRR [complaint], n.d.
      - Communication from Leland Stanford to the Committee on Corporations of the Senate, Jan. 22, 1894
      - Supplementary statement by Leland Stanford to United States Pacific Railway Commission (re indebtedness of CPRR to the Government), 1887
      - Report (from the Pacific Railway Commission) on the CPRR, 1890 [Senate Report No. 293]
      - Proofs for pp. 103-142 of unnamed account of legal suit involving Huntington, Colton, and Stanford
      - Blank form for denial of railroad passes, 1869
    - Central Pacific Railroad Company: Southern Pacific Company, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Clippings on Stanford and S.P.
      - Resolution of thanks to L. Stanford from Board of Directors, 1890
      - Agreement re S. P. Bd. of Directors and officers and re cooperation for election of Stanford to Senate, Feb 1890; [mss copy with Huntington's address]
      - Agreement re S. P. Bd. of Directors and officers and re cooperation for election of Stanford to Senate, Feb 1890; [mss copy on Stanford's letterhead]
    - Central Pacific Railroad Company: telegraph books, 1868- 1869 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Two books of telegrams
      - Typescript copies of other telegrams (source unknown)
    - Central Pacific Railroad Company: telegraph books - photocopied (to be used for further copying) (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Two books of telegrams
      - Typescript copies of other telegrams (source unknown)
  - Central Pacific Division of the Atlantic and Pacific Telegraph Company, 1874 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Four telegrams (letterhead shows L. Stanford, President)
  - Checks, miscellaneous, 1867-1893 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Personal checks, most made out to Jane Stanford or to "Self," 1867, 1888- 1893; includes one to Chester Griswood, of the American Protective Tariff League, 1867-1893
  - Manzanita Water Company, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Agreement with Archbishop Patrick W. Riordan to provide water to St. Patrick's Seminary in Menlo Park (photocopy)
  - Monohan, John suit, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 1890, Feb. 11: telegram L. Stanford to Ariel Lathrop
    - 1890, Feb. 11: letter H. C. Nash to Ariel Lathrop
    - 1890, March 5: copy of 1876 lease, L. Stanford to John Monohan (Tobin Tract, San Mateo County)
  - Pacific Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1868- 1872 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 1868: clip showing L. Stanford president
    - 1868, Dec. 10: policy on Edward Price signed by L. Stanford, with two receipts, 1869-70
    - 1868: photocopy of policy on Leland Stanford (with historical note on reverse)
    - 1872, July 19: deed Pacific Mutual to John and Edward Coleman
  - Palo Alto Farm, 1877-1895 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - assessment lists for Stock Farm (San Francisquito Rancho), 1877-1880
    - Agreement, L. Stanford, Chas. Wehner, and R. Farrill on building of Mayfield-Searsville Road thru the Palo Alto Rancho, 1888 Feb 11
    - catalog for action sale of trotting colts and fillies, 1895 Apr 10
    - label for hock, Palo Alto vineyard, Undated
    - list of employees and supposed amount of salaries, Sept
  - Palo Alto Farm - mausoleum, 1887-1888 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - letter (copy) Wetmore & Morse Granite Co. to Caterson & Clark, 1887-11-12
    - specifications, Caterson & Clark, 1887-11-12
    - telegram (copy) L. Stanford to Robert Caterson, 1887-11-14
    - letter, Robert Caterson to J. E. Gates, 1888-09-12
  - Placer County Justice of the Peace, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Legal papers from the case of James Cole; Leland Stanford, J.P.
  - Receipt book (blank), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - San Mateo County property taxes, 1889-1902 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Tax assessments and bills
  - Stocks and bonds, A through F, 1868-1899 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Bodie Bluff Consolidation Mining Co., 186-
    - Capital Savings Bank of Sacramento, 1879
    - Capital Woolen Mills, 1869
    - Coal Road Construction Co. (Kentucky), 1881
    - Colorado Steam Navigation Company, 1877
    - Contract Finance Company, 1868, 1873
    - Cornell Watch Company, 1875
    - Donner Lumber & Boom Co. [to Jane Stanford], 1899
    - Financial Improvement Company, 1884
  - Stocks and bonds, G through W, 1871-1897 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Gilmore Angora Goat Breeking Association, 1875
    - International Construction Company, 1884
    - Mission Bay Bridge Company, 1872-79
    - Orleans Hills Vinicultural Association, 1869
    - Pacific Steam Agricutural Manufacturing Co., 1883
    - Riverside Bathing Association of Sacramento, 1874
    - Riverside Hotel and Turnpike Co., 1874
    - San Francisco Transfer Company, 1871
    - Southern Development Company, 1881-1897
    - Western Development Company, 1879-1889
  - Stocks and bonds, railroads (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Chicago, Rock Island & Pacific Railroad Company
    - Kentucy and South Atlantic Railway Company
    - Newport News and Mississippi Valley Company
    - Salt Lake & Fort Douglass Railway Company
    - Yosemite Valley Railroad Company
  - Sweeney and McClosky vs. Leland Stanford: transcript on appeal, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Vina Ranch, 1889-1901 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Blank bills, undated
    - Ads for Vina brandy
    - Report by Prof. E. W. Hilgard on "Fraser Electro-Magnetic Process", 1887
    - newspaper proofsheet of story on Vina (incomplete), 1889-11-25
    - letter F. B. Vaden to F. W. Carey re barrels delivered, 1899-05-31
    - list of workers "let out", 1893-09-01
    - list of wines shipped, 1901 Jan 1
    - payroll (Palo Alto Dept., Winery, Doyle Camp, Distillery, Boarding house, Vina Ranch, Copeland Ranch, Vineyard), September, no year
  - Warm Springs Ranch, 1869-1870 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - letter, James T. Stratton to A. Cohen, 1869, May 10:
    - agreement Alfred A. Cohen to L. Stanford on sale of Warm Springs, 1869 Sep 2
    - field notes of James T. Stratton of tract sold by Bright to Palmer, 1869 Sep 24
    - letter, A. G. Carrie to McCullough & Boyd re return of title, 1870 Jan 10
  - Cesnola's Collection Metropolitan Museum of Art New York. List of duplicates sold to Hon. Leland Stanford, (photocopy) (Box 11)
- Political papers, Series 4
  - Governor of California - clippings, 1862-1889 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Governor of California - documents signed as governor, 1862-1863 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 1862, Sept. 24: appointment of John Mitchell as Cmmr. of Deeds
    - 1862, Nov. 4: certificate of election of William Corey, Placer County Clerk
    - 1863, Sept. 29: travel pass of Adam Bock
    - 1863, Nov. 5: proclamation of Thanksgiving (printed)
  - Governor of California - printed documents, 1862-1863 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - 1862, January 10: Inaugural Address [photocopy]
    - 1862, November 1: proclamation of Thanksgiving
    - 1863, January: Annual Message of Leland Stanford
    - 1863, December: Second Annual Message of Leland Stanford (2 copies)
    - 1863, January: Communication from Governor Stanford to the Legislature with Correspondence; re payment of California's quota of direct tax
  - Governor of California - Republican Party tickets, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Republican Ticket, Third District: Leland Stanford and James F. Kennedy (Lt. Gov.)
    - Republican Ticket: Leland Stanford and F. F. Chellis (Lt. Gov.)
  - U. S. Senator - Congressional committee calendar, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Notebook for Senate Committe on Public Buildings and Grounds
  - U. S. Senator - Congressional reports, 1888-1892 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Committee on Naval Affairs re bill on desertion
    - Committee on Public Buildings and Grounds re buildings in Dallas; Ogden, Utah; Fresno, CA; Alameda, CA; Battle Creek, MI; and Lansing, MI
  - U. S. Senator - Journal, 1885-1893 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Brief entries in handwriting of H. C. Nash re leg. bills, receipt of salary, travels, appointments, letters written, callers, general activities, 1885; with typed list of Stanford's movements, 1888-1893
  - U. S. Senator - speeches, 1886-1892 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Interstate Commerce, 1886
    - Cooperation, 1887
    - Education, 1890
    - Government Loans on Real Estate (2 copies - one printed in Australia), 1890
  - U. S. Senator - Young Men's Central Republican Club, resolution of support, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Jeffers, L. G., statement endorsing Stanford as presidential candidate, Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Five pages (ts) recounting Stanford's political and business life and his qualifications as presidential candidate; written in Washington, DC
  - Miscellaneous political clippings (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - On Stanford's interstate commerce speech, 1887
    - On A. S. Smith's appointment as Postmaster of Marysville, Undated
- Speeches and interviews, Series 5
  - Cooperation of Labor, an interview with Senator Stanford.. .New York Tribune, 1887; Pamphlet (2 copies) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - The Great Question, an interview with Senator Leland Stanford on Money, includes views of Col. Rickey and "The Doctor", undated; Pamphlet (3 copies); and acid-free xerox copy (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - The Land Loan Bill, interview with Hon. Leland Stanford of California, undated; Pamphlet (2 copies) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Unidentified speech attributed to Stanford, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Holograph copy (not in LS hand), on Republican politics and the tariff; given at San Jose
- University matters, Series 6
  - LSJU letterpress book: outgoing letters signed mostly by H. C. Nash, Of note:, 1891-1892 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1891, May 11: Nash to Jordan re houses available for professors
    - 1891, June 22: re contracting bids on cottages and plans for girls' dormitory
    - 1891, July 14: Nash to Jenkins re O.L. Elliott wishes to occupy Cedro Cottage temporarily
    - 1891, July 16: Nash to Mrs. Boye re Jewett Collection
    - 1891, Oct. 30: Stanford to Shepley, Rutan & Coolidge re hiring Mr. Austin, beginning of school
    - 1891, Nov. 9: Stanford to Olmsted "improving the grounds in accordance with your plans"
  - Correspondence
    - Outgoing
      - Outgoing correspondence to Jordan, D. S., 1891 (Box 6, Folder 1)
        - thinks 15 professors enough to open with, 1891 Apr 13
        - decided to name boys dormitory Encina Hall, 1891 May 9:
        - approves prospectus; names dormitories for oak trees, 1891 May 16:
        - will have accommodations for 80 girls, 1891 May 21:
        - thinks 4-5 thousand dollars sufficient to start library, 1891 May 26:
        - do not engage Nissen, 1891 May 30:
        - defer agricultural branch, 1891 June 1:
        - no suggestions for circular no. 4, 1891 June 10:
      - Outgoing correspondence to Jordan, D. S., 1892 Jan-May (Box 6, Folder 2)
        - recommends Dr. Charles of Menlo Park, 1892 Jan 1
        - Dr. Grau and Miss Ames on payroll; mistress of Roble Hall; pleased with address, 1892 Jan 1
        - must exercise own judgment on engaging profs. White, Dudley, Jenks and Angell, 1892 Feb 17
        - payment of professors for outside lectures; steam heat for gymnasium; getting President White as lecturer; finding meteors, 1892 Feb 17
        - suspend arrangements for heating gymnasium, 1892 Feb 18
        - introduces Mr. & Mrs. Morris K. Jessup, 1892 Mar 16
        - will be in Palo Alto in April, 1892 Mar 29
        - remuneration for Pres. White, 1892 May 8:
        - faculty appointments [signature cut out], 1892 May 10:
        - case of Miss Hay, 1892 May 11:
        - H.C. Nash to Jordan inclosing recommendations approved by Sen. Stanford, 1892 May 15:
        - $5 a week sufficient for board, 1892 May 23:
        - to hasten construction of buildings; too many professors and assistants, 1892 May 23:
        - sends address in Paris, 1892 May 24:
        - (tel): approval of lease form, 1892 May 26
        - issue of students' board, 1892 May 26:
        - introduces Wilson Evans, 1892 May 29:
        - Prof. Gale out of place in mechanical engineering; pleased with letter from Pres. White, 1892 May 29:
        - students' expenses must not exceed $5 per week, 1892 May 30:
      - Outgoing correspondence to Jordan, D. S., 1892 Aug-1893 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - approval of appointment of Dr. Murray, 1892 Aug 8
        - experiments vs lectures; belief in immortality of the soul essential to civilization; golden rule foundation of true humanitarianism, 1892 Aug 24
        - students to pay only actual cost of living; our university to be of high grade; more dormitory space for girls is needed, 1892 Aug 24
        - does not want pay for tuition; possibility of students boarding themselves, 1892 Aug 30
        - sailing on the Majestic; visit from Pres. White, 1892 Sep 28
        - suggests ex-sen. Edmunds as commencement speaker, 1893 Mar 10
        - employees may go cheerfully if they can better themselves; teach only the fundamental principles of law; President Harrison and arbitration, 1893 Mar 10
        - regrets Prof. Swain leaving, willing to offer him position of Vice-President or Assistant to the Pres., 1893 Apr 3
      - Outgoing correspondence to Sloss, Leon, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
        - L. Stanford to Sloss inviting him to become trustee, 1891 Nov 30
        - Nash to Sloss enclosing deed of appointment, 1891 Dec 8
        - Deed of appointment signed by Sloss, 1891 Dec 10
        - two envelopes
      - Outgoing correspondence to Stebbins, Horatio, 1887 (Box 6, Folder 5)
        - invitation to cornerstone laying
      - Outgoing correspondence to Tubbs, A. L., 1885 (Box 6, Folder 6)
        - Letter and telegram re appointment as trustee
      - Outgoing correspondence to Vrooman, Henry, 1885 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        - Letters and telegrams re appointment as trustee
      - Outgoing correspondence to White, Andrew, 1890- 1892; Photocopies; originals at Cornell University (Box 6, Folder 8)
        - 1890 May 5: teaching of religion and other university matters
        - 1891May 6: endorsement of Jordan
        - 1892 Feb. 2: letters of introduction and recommendations for travel routes west
    - Incoming
      - Axelrood, Max, 1885- 1887 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - A, 1885-1889 (Box 6, Folder 10)
        - Abbiati, Albino
        - Adams, Gertrude
        - Allen, Charles H.
        - Ames, E. S.
        - Amsden, E.
        - Anderson, George L
        - Anderson, S. T.
        - Andrews, Jas. Douglas
        - Ardley, Henry T.
        - Arnold, B. W.
        - Arnold, Mary E.
      - Ba - Bl, 1885-1889 (Box 6, Folder 11)
        - Badlam, Alexander
        - Bailey, John F.
        - Baker, Samuel C.
        - Baldwin, Henry
        - Bar, Mrs.
        - Barton, Robert
        - Beck, Alexander
        - Beckwith, Mrs. C. C.
        - Bee, S. Louis
        - Beecher, E. B.
        - Belle, S. B.
        - Bennett, C. R.
        - Bentley, M. Louise
        - Blackiston, John
        - Blaikie, William
        - Blaufied, B. T.
        - Blumer, John
      - Bo - Bz, 1885-1889 (Box 6, Folder 12)
        - Boardman, Mrs.
        - Boyce, Mrs. A. A.
        - Boyce, H. H.
        - Boyd, James H.
        - Briggs, R. S.: 5/15/1889 on costs of stone for Encina Hall
        - Brown, H. A.
        - Brown, Wilfred L.: 10/14/1886 on stone in Alameda quarry
        - Buckler, T. H.
        - Bullock, Robert W.
      - C, 1885-1889 (Box 6, Folder 13)
        - Calkins, C. G.
        - Cambern, S. M.
        - Cilley, Henry
        - Cilley, Mrs. Henry
        - Claghorn, Henry S.
        - Clark, E. A.: 11/24/1888 on his idea of gallery of painting on evolution
        - Clark, Willie
        - Clarke, Samuel J.
        - Clay, Cecil
        - Clements, Mrs. M. R.
        - Cluth, A. A.
        - Coleman, R. A.
        - Conway, Richard M.: 12/23/1885 has collection of autographs to sell
        - Cordell, Edward C.
        - Crouch, Henry C.
      - Di Cesnola, Louis Parma, 1885 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - D - E, 1885 (Box 6, Folder 15)
        - Dalzell, Charles
        - Dalzell, James M.
        - Davis, Floyd
        - Dawson, N. H. R.
        - De Garno, Charles
        - De Wolf, John: 12/17/1885 requesting job as surveyor and landscape architect
        - Denken, T. H.
        - Eastland, J.
        - Eddy, W. M.
        - Edwards, H. H.
        - Eells, James
        - Estee, M. M.
        - Everette, Willis E.: 4/28/1887 offering for sale his collection of Eskimo artifacts
      - F - G, 1885-1889 (Box 6, Folder 16)
        - Fairchild, James H.